I've hinted at this so much already.
我都暗示成这样了
And you're still playing dumb.
你还装傻
Then I might as well be direct.
那我只能索性挑明
I respect you.
我很尊重你
I hope you can respect me too.
也请你同样尊重我
I have a fiancé.
我有未婚夫了
We'll be getting married soon.
很快就会结婚
No matter what was on your mind,
不管您有什么想法
I can only say I'm sorry.
我只能说抱歉了
Are you referring to
你是说那个
Mr. Ji?
纪行长
You know, Xiaoning,
你知道吗筱柠
the first time I met you,
我第一次见你的时候
I watched you
我看你在那儿
focusing on the printer.
认真地摆弄打印机
You observed that I like coffee
观察我喜欢喝咖啡
and don't enjoy tea.
不喜欢喝茶
I thought you're an aspirant woman
我一度以为你是一个
who relied on your own efforts.
靠自己努力上进的女人
But you're smarter than I expected.
但你比我想象得聪明
Leveraging a close relationship
跟着领导
with the boss is indeed a shortcut
确实是一个
to accelerate your career path.
向上爬的捷径
Besides,
再说了
aren't you still not officially married?
你不还没正式结婚吗
Since you're a smart girl,
既然你是一个聪明的人
you should know
我可以告诉你
that I'm capable
他能给你的
of anything
我一样能给你
he can provide
他不能给你的
or he can't.
我也能给你
Although he's in charge of a branch,
虽然他是个行长
he's just someone on the payroll.
但也就是一个拿年薪的
But I'm different.
但我不一样
I returned from abroad
我从国外回来
to manage such a large enterprise.
经营这么大的企业
I need someone to help me
我需要有一个人
oversee internal operations.
帮我把持内事
We both have our needs to fulfill.
我们各取所需
A fair arrangement, huh?
不好吗
Are you finished?
说完了
Supposedly,
本来呢
you are my client.
你是我的客户
I should show you respect.
我应该尊重你
And I should do my utmost
我应该尽全力地
to make our partnership work.
促成这次合作
If you
方案
don't like the proposal,
你不满意我可以改
I'm open to revisions,
一次不行
no matter
我就改第二次
how many times.
第三次第四次都可以
If it still doesn't
直到你满意为止
satisfy you in the end,
如果一直不满意
I guess I'll have to give in.
我只能认输
We are in a partnership.
我们是合作关系
No more, no less.
不可能有其他可能性
You're saying I was leveraging
你刚才说
a close relationship with my boss.
我跟着领导往上爬
Not only did you insult me,
不只侮辱了我
but insulted my fiancé.
还侮辱了我的未婚夫
So,
所以
I don't think you deserve
我觉得我也没有必要
my respect.
尊重你
Mr. Fu,
小付总
your behavior
你的为人啊
has truly opened my eyes.
真是让我刮目相看
Xiaoning!
筱柠
Wait a moment!
你等一下筱柠
Behave yourself!
小付总请你自重
Is this your way of playing hard to get?
欲擒故纵是吗
You know what,
我告诉你
I actually find that quite appealing.
我很吃这一套
It just fuels
你这样反而
my desire to conquer.
让我更有征服欲
Ji Yuheng!
纪昱恒
I'm really sorry.
对不起啊
I screwed this up.
是我自己没有处理好
It's all my fault.
都怪我
But you're a bit impulsive today.
你今天真的有点冲动
I'm worried he might file a complaint.
我怕他投诉你
You just became the president...
你刚当上行长万一
None of that matters!
这些根本就不重要
Tu Xiaoning, you hear me?
涂筱柠都不重要
To me,
对我来说
your safety tops all others.
你才是最重要的
I won't let anyone hurt you
我不允许任何人伤害你
or bully you.
也不允许任何人欺负你
You have no idea
你根本就不知道
how deep and enduring
我对你的爱
my love for you truly is.
有多深有多久
Alright, alright.
好了 好了
I know.
我知道
Since a year ago,
从一年前
when we met again...
我们两个第一次见面
Not just a year ago,
不是一年前
but eleven years ago.
是十一年前
Since our high school days,
从高中的时候
the only girl I've truly loved
我心里唯一爱的人
has been you.
就是你
Follow me.
我带你去个地方
Why did you
怎么突然
bring me here out of the blue?
带我到这儿来呀
Because this is the place where
因为这是十一年前
I fell for you at first sight 11 years ago.
我对你一见钟情的地方
Xiaoning,
筱柠
there are certain things
有些话我现在
that I have to let you know.
必须要说出来
In 2013,
二零一三年
on your birthday,
你生日
I made you a birthday gift, but
我做了一个生日礼物
I never had the courage to give it to you.
但一直都没有送出手
It was a clay doll.
是一个泥塑娃娃
Is it...
是
The one I've seen before?
是我见过的那个吗
Isn't that your dream girl?
那不是你的白月光吗
That was actually you.
那是你
My dream girl
白月光
is you.
也是你
Actually, the first time I met you
其实我第一次遇见你
was when
是在
I was eighteen.
十八岁的那年
One afternoon,
一个下午
after P.E. class,
体育课之后
you're drinking water by the pool.
你在水池旁边喝水
Tu Xiaoning!
涂筱柠
Let's go!
走啦
Coming!
来啦
Please.
到你了
That was the first time
那是我第一次
I heard your name,
听到了你的名字
and laid eyes on you.
也是第一次看到你
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Also the first time that
更是第一次
I realized what
让我知道了
it truly means to feel a heartbeat.
什么叫做心动
Then,
再到后来
my father committed suicide.
我爸爸自杀之后
It took me into
那是我人生当中
the darkest time of my life.
最灰暗的一段时光
That evening, I was sitting there,
那天傍晚我就坐在那儿
you showed up.
然后你出现了
Kitty?
肉松
Don't!
你别冲动
Are you alright?
没事吧
It shouldn't be injured.
应该没伤到它
I'm asking about you.
我是问你
Are you OK?
你没事吧
Ji Yuheng,
纪昱恒
is that right?
是吧
I've actually heard
我其实听到过
some things about you,
你的一些事情
just occasionally from others.
就是偶尔听别人说起
I'm not very clear on the details,
确实也不是很清楚
but I wanna tell you that
但是我就是想跟你说
you've got to look ahead in life.
凡事你得往前看
Dwelling on the past
你一直往后看
will only bring you loss,
就经常面对失去
but focusing on the future
但是往前看的话
can lead to
就会有很多
all sorts of new gains.
不一样的收获
You are like a ray of light.
你就像是一束光一样
That light illuminated my life
那束光照亮了我
and saved me.
也拯救了我
Later on,
再到后来
I found myself unconsciously drawn to you.
我会不自觉地去关注你
In my eyes,
那时候在我眼里
you're radiant,
你很明媚
warm,
很温暖
and incredibly brave.
也很勇敢
When we both went to college,
后来我们都上了大学
I could only catch glimpses of you
我只能零星地
through messages
在同学群里面
in our class group chat.
看到你的消息
For a time, I missed you deeply.
有段时间我特别地想你
So I made up my mind
所以我下定决心
to seek you out.
我要去找你
I went to your school,
我去了你的学校
but I was still late.
但还是晚了一步
Kiss!
亲一个
Then,
再后来
I went abroad.
出了国
Studying abroad alone,
一个人去留学
and living on my own.
一个人生活
But I still quietly
但是我还是默默地
kept an eye on your updates.
看着你的消息
One night,
直到有一天晚上
I saw your new post,
我看到你发了一条动态
saying you're back single.
你说你恢复单身了
Hey!
喂
Please book
回去的机票
my return ticket as well.
帮我一块订了吧
The sooner, the better.
越快越好
I booked a ticket as soon as I could.
我第一时间订了票回来
I didn't want to miss out again.
不想再错过了
We're about to meet,
我们就快要见面了吧
Tu Xiaoning.
涂筱柠
Then why didn't you
那你回来为什么
come to me when you just got back?
不第一时间来找我
Because you mentioned
因为我看到你说
that you needed time
你需要时间
to sort things out.
去整理一下自己
So I didn't want to intrude.
所以我不想去打扰你
Until later,
直到后来
you wanted
你说你想
to start a new relationship,
重新开始一段感情
even looking for
甚至开始寻找
a marriage partner.
结婚对象的时候
I realized I couldn't wait any longer.
我知道我不能再等了
I didn't want to miss out again.
我不想再错过
Thanks.
谢谢
That's Mr. Ji from compliance,
那可是合规部的纪老师
here to audit us specifically.
来检查的专管我们
Audit us?
专管我们
Right.
对
Miss Wang, right?
汪小姐是吧
Please come this way.
这边请
Sir, what can I assist you with?
大爷您办什么业务
Hello.
您好
Please come this way.
这边请
So,
所以
the first time
我们第一次
we met at the matchmaking site...
在相亲公园见面
I initially thought
我本来还以为
we just happened to cross paths.
我们两个是偶然遇见
Surprisingly,
但实际上
you came back specifically for me.
你是专门为了我回来的
Later on,
后来
I brought up the idea of marriage.
我跟你提出想跟你结婚
I thought you felt the same way
我以为你跟我一样
that we were simply
只是觉得我们两个
a good match,
很合适
with the excitement of
怀揣着
opening a blind box, stepping into the
开盲盒的心情
next chapter of our relationship.
步入下一段关系
I can say that we're classmates,
那我可不可以理解为
it makes us feel at ease
我们俩是同学
with each other.
知根知底
In marriage,
婚姻中
it doesn't have to revolve around love.
不一定非要有爱情
Comfort and stability
舒适稳定
are also very important.
也很重要
But in truth,
而实际上
you had already decided
你早就打定主意
to marry me.
要娶我
What matters is not
不是因为合适
conditions, but love.
而是因为爱我
Here are all my documents.
这是我全部的证件
The property deed,
有房本
diplomas,
学历证明
no-criminal record,
无犯罪证明
credit reports,
征信记录
and my bank statements
以及最近几年的
for recent years.
存款明细
I realize this
我知道这种方式
might seem a bit inappropriate,
可能有些欠妥当
but it's the fastest way
但是这是我能想到的
I could think of
最快速地让两位
to help you both get to know me.
能够了解我的方式了
You know,
我说
I love you.
我喜欢你
Come on,
不争气
why am I crying?
怎么哭了
It's been such a long time.
这么长时间了
Mr. Ji,
纪先生
you've always given me plenty of space,
你一直给我足够的空间
and a sense of security.
足够的安全感
You've been waiting for me
是一直在等我
to fall in love with you, haven't you?
爱上你的那一刻吗
So it's not something
所以这一切
like a sudden reunion
根本就不是什么
after a long time.
久别重逢
You've been planning this for a long time,
是你早就蓄谋已久了
innit?
是不是
Silly.
傻瓜
Of course, it's also a reunion.
当然也是久别重逢
But you know,
只是这个久对我来说
I waited too long.
有点太过漫长了
I was so afraid
长到我怕
that I might miss you.
我就这么错过你了
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
你为什么不早告诉我呀
I thought
我还以为
someone else was your dream girl.
别人是你的白月光呢
You didn't even explain it to me.
你也不给我解释一下
How could you do that?
你这个人怎么这样啊
Our feelings are
我还以为我们感情
getting stronger.
越来越好
I don't wanna bring
那些年少的这事
those in the past up.
不说也就罢了
They wouldn't
也不会影响到我们
affect us.
现在相爱
Besides,
再说了
in front of Tang Yuhui that night,
唐羽卉的事情的时候
I also mentioned that
我不也说了吗
I fell in love with you
我对你
at first sight.
是一见钟情
But it took me so long
这个一见钟情
to find out about this.
是不是太久了
After all these years,
这么多年
in this relationship,
在这段感情里
you've always taken 99 steps on your own,
你总是自己迈九十九步
waiting for me to take that final step.
等着我踏出最后一步
You've been through a lot.
你辛苦了
And you must
一个人
have felt
在这段感情里
incredibly lonely.
走得很孤单吧
I believe it's worth it.
我觉得很值得
Honestly, I've always
其实我一直
dreamed of this moment.
都很憧憬这一刻
I think it deserves
我觉得应该
a bit of ceremony.
有一点仪式感才对
But Xiaoning,
但是筱柠
I truly can't wait any longer.
我真的等不了了
Even if I have to take 100 steps,
就算是我走一百步
that's perfectly fine.
也没关系
As long as you give me a sign,
只要你给我一个肯定
just a nod,
点点头
or a smile.
给我一个微笑
So, Miss Tu,
所以涂小姐
will you marry me?
你愿意嫁给我吗
Yes.
我愿意啊
Mr. Ji.
纪先生
Put it on me now.
快给我戴上
Thank you,
谢谢你啊
Mr. Ji.
纪先生
Thank you so much
谢谢你让我知道
for
原来
letting me know
在那么久以前
that your love
就有一个人
for me
一直喜欢着我
has lasted for so long.
珍惜着我
Thank you.
辛苦了
I love you.
我爱你
Mr. Ji.
纪先生
Actually,
其实
I originally planned
本来是打算
to propose to you
在度假的时候
during vacation.
跟你求婚的
But today, I just
但是今天实在是
couldn't hold back.
有点忍不住了
It must be
想着就得是今天
completed today.
就得是现在
I can't wait to be recognized
让你能够允许我
as your husband.
成为你的合法丈夫
So,
那怎么
you've been
你这戒指
carrying this ring around
走到哪儿
with you everywhere?
都带到哪儿
Not really.
当然不是了
I
我呢
specifically hired a
专门请了一个
wedding planner,
婚礼策划师
hoping to create
想着给你留下一个
unforgettable
很难忘的
and truly ceremonial
且很有仪式感的
proposal experience for you.
求婚仪式
But this afternoon,
但是今天下午
I was genuinely worried about you,
实在是有点担心你
so I stood them up.
所以放了他们鸽子
What's so funny?
笑什么
What's wrong with me laughing?
我笑怎么啦
I'm just so happy.
我开心啊
I'm thrilled
我开心
that you can so confidently
你可以这么坚定地
choose me.
选择我
Hello, Mr. Yu.
喂 余总
Hey, Xiaoning,
老同学
the small loan
小额贷的事情
has been sealed.
我已经办好了
Just want to let you know.
跟你汇报一声
Thanks.
多谢了
No problem.
不用客气
I should be thanking you
我还得谢谢你
for choosing Dairui.
选择我们代瑞银行呢
If you ever need any
以后有什么
financial services in the future,
资金上的业务需要
feel free to reach out to me.
欢迎随时来找我
Sounds good.
好
No problem at all.
没问题
By the way,
对
there's one more thing.
还有件事
Last time,
上次
you talked about
你跟我说
me and certain some guy.
我和那谁
Were you referring to Ji Yuheng?
是我跟纪昱恒吗
That's all in the past.
都过去的事了
Why bring it up?
想它干什么呢
Just tell me.
你快点说啊
If you don't,
你要是不说的话
I won't be able to help you
以后贷款的事
with any loan matters.
我恕不接待啊
Oh, no!
别
I'll say it, OK?
我说 我说还不行吗
Back then, I was playing a prank on you.
当年我不是欺负你吗
Then,
然后
he beat me up
他放学就把我给
after school.
揍了一顿
We can't judge a book by its cover, huh?
真是人不可貌相啊
He beat you up?
他揍你
Yeah.
是啊
He even said,
他还说
if I bothered you again,
我要是再敢找你麻烦
or made his love
或者把他喜欢你的事
for you public,
跟大家说
he would report me
他就把我欺负你那事
to the school,
举报到学校去
and have them check the camera.
让学校查监控
Who knows,
说不定
I might have even got expelled!
我还得退学呢
Whoa, you were that intimidating?
你这么厉害啊
You even dared to bully the school bully!
还敢欺负威胁校霸
What?
啥
I bullied the school bully?
我威胁校霸
No,
不是
I mean,
我的意思是说
weren't you the school bully?
你不是校霸吗
He really got some guts
他怎么胆子这么大
to bully you.
还敢威胁你呀
Why are you so interested
你怎么这么关注
in his history?
纪昱恒的事啊
No way!
不会吧
Could it be that
难道当年你对他
you had feelings for him?
有这么个意思啊
She didn't back then,
当年是没有
but she does now.
不过现在已经有了
In terms of business,
以后工作的事情
please call my wife
就工作时间
during office hours.
再给我老婆打电话
We are out.
挂了
What wife?
什么老婆啊
We're not officially married yet.
我们还没合法呢
Let's get registered tomorrow.
明天就去领证
Now come home with me.
现在跟我回家
Wasn't that Ji Yuheng's voice?
这不是纪昱恒的声音吗
Wife?
老婆
So...
难道
Hello.
您好
Here's our number.
这是我们的号码牌
Documents, thanks.
资料
Our photos are among them.
里面也有照片
Are you both first-time married?
你俩是初婚吗
Yeah.
对
This is the photo you are using?
就用这个照片啊
It's not as natural
还没你俩现在
as you two look now.
笑得自然呢
The marriage certificate
这结婚证啊
is quite important.
还是很重要的
How about...
那 那要不
We take another one?
重新拍一个
OK, sir and ma'am,
好嘞 两位新人啊
please get a bit closer.
咱们亲密一点啊
Closer.
靠近一点
Good.
好
Um...
靠
too much actually.
倒也不用靠那么近啊
It's like you're stacked together.
看起来两个人叠一块了
Keep more distance.
按说还是要分开点
Exactly!
对
Alright!
好嘞
Smile.
开心
Sir.
新郎
Your happiness is shining through.
你这开心溢于言表
I totally get it.
我能理解啊
But your smile is so big!
你这笑太大了
While taking the photo,
这拍着 拍着
all we see are your big white teeth!
就看你这两颗大白牙了
Tone it down a bit.
收一点
Just a little.
稍微收一点
Right!
对
Ma'am.
新娘
You're leaning on his shoulder.
都靠到新郎肩膀上了
That's not
拍出来
symmetrical!
那不对称啊
Perfect!
对
Smile, come on!
开心 来
This looks great!
这样非常好啊
Three!
三
Two!
二
One!
一
Not bad!
不错 不错
One more time!
咱们再来一张
Three!
三
Two!
二
One!
一
Mr. Ji,
纪先生
We are officially
我们现在
married now!
可是合法夫妻了
Let's take a photo
拍张照片
to commemorate this moment.
纪念一下吧
Come on!
来
Cool.
好啊
But we're still missing something.
不过还少一个东西
I'll go grab it now.
我现在去拿
Just wait for me.
等我一下啊
Guess who I just saw?
你们猜猜我看到谁啦
I saw Mrs. Xu's daughter
我看到小徐的女儿
at the registry office!
在民政局
Congratulations,
恭喜啦
Mrs. Ji.
纪太太
Thank you!
谢谢
Here,
来
one for each of us.
一人一个
Go!
二 三
Happily married!
新婚快乐
Yay!
快乐
Nonsense!
胡说八道
They only
我女儿女婿
got married a year ago.
才结婚一年多
They're so in love.
感情好着呢
Divorce? Ridiculous!
怎么可能去离婚呢
Seriously.
是真的
I saw them
我亲眼看他们
walk out of the registry office
从民政局出来
and go their own ways.
然后各走各的
I know
小徐
it hurts.
我知道你心里难过
But kids are all grown up.
但是孩子们都大了
They don't always have to tell us
做决定前不告诉我们
everything before making choices.
也是正常的
I'm not upset.
我有什么可难过的
I know better than
他们感情好不好
anyone how they
别人不知道
feel about each other.
我还能不知道吗
You know.
我跟你讲
You must have made a mistake.
你肯定是看错了
I'm gonna check with my daughter.
我现在就去找我女儿
I'll show you
我拍了结婚证
their marriage certificate.
我给你发过去
Nonsense.
无聊
What the hell?
什么鬼
Where are you going?
你 你干吗去
I'm going to Xiaoning's place,
我找筱柠去啊
and snap a picture
我拿结婚证
of their wedding certificate.
我现在就拍给她
That's what the evidence says.
我啪啪打她的脸我
C'mon,
你都说了
no need to worry
她那是胡说八道
about too much.
你理她干什么呀
A fact is a fact.
假的真不了真的假不了
But I must
我不理她她理我呀
put a stop
她在这儿吧 吧 吧
to this.
胡说八道
I can't just ignore it.
我不管吗
Dad.
爸
Mom, dad.
爸 妈
We're home.
爸妈我们回来啦
Any good eats?
有没有做好吃的呀
Where...
你俩
have you...
去
See,
你看这两人
they're all lovey-dovey.
这不好着呢吗
I knew she was full of it.
我就说她说的是假的
Check out these beautiful flowers.
你看这花多好看啊
Haven't gotten any in forever.
我都多久没收到花了
My kids are so thoughtful.
还是我女儿女婿贴心啊
Glad you like them.
我妈喜欢就好
Put them in a pretty pot.
去把花插上吧
I'll buy you more.
回头再给你买
Make them look nice.
插好看点啊
Have a seat.
坐 坐 坐
Gotta take a break.
我休息一下
What a busy morning!
这一早上给我折腾的呀
I'm telling you,
我今天都被气死了
I was pissed off!
我跟你讲
You don't know
你都不知道
what a ridiculous thing happened today.
今天发生一多离谱的事
Ms. Zhao from
就那隔壁楼的那个
the next
老赵阿姨
building called,
给我打一电话
saying she saw
说今天看见
you two at the registry office
你俩去民政局
getting a divorce.
去离婚去了
Unbelievable.
离谱
Definitely!
是不是离谱
It's crazy, isn't it?
你们也觉得离谱是不是
I told her
我跟你讲
straight up
我狠狠就怼了她
that it's impossible,
我说怎么可能呢
'cause you're
我女儿女婿感情这么好
so in love.
我跟你讲
Later, show me that cert,
一会儿你就把那结婚证
I gotta take a photo
给我拿出来
and show her
我必须拍个照
how wrong she is.
必须啪啪打她的脸
Wait...
不
Why
你俩咋
the silence?
不说话呢
Mom.
妈
We
我俩吧
did go there.
确实去民政局了
What for?
去那儿干吗呀
Dad, mom.
爸 妈
There's something
有一件事情
we need to
确实需要
be honest about with you.
跟你们坦白一下
Dad.
爸
Mom.
妈
About the marriage cert,
结婚证的这件事情
I have to
我们确实需要
apologize for not
跟你们说一声抱歉
telling you right away.
我们也应该第一时间
That's totally
把这件事情
my bad.
告诉你们二位
But you know,
但后来也因为
many have happened since then,
发生了很多事情
I just couldn't find
一直都没有找到一个
the right moment.
合适的时机告诉你们
But over this past year,
不过我们这一年呢
we've really got to know
互相更了解对方了
each other better, and we feel
我认为我们这个婚
more committed now.
结得更有责任感了
Right.
是
It was
你俩
a false alarm.
虚惊一场
But it ended well.
不过好在结果是好的
Just
咱呢
forget about it.
就别再往心里去了啊
It ended well.
结果是好的
I'm bummed.
没办法不放在心上
My girl's all grown up
我女儿现在长大了
and
有什么事
keeping secrets.
也不跟我说
First, secretly getting married,
现在可以瞒着我结婚
next,
过几年
keeping a granddaughter
说不定生了个孙女
from me till
都到了十八岁了
she's 18.
也拦着不让我见
Come on.
你看你
I'm so
我的心
disappointed.
是寒透了
Mom, you're going overboard.
妈你这越说越离谱了啊
Wait,
我知道
is this about us
是不是因为让你在
embarrassing you in front of Ms. Zhao?
赵阿姨面前丢面子了
How about
要不咱们这样
I take a photo
咱们拍张照片
and fake the date
把那个日期修改一下
to last year?
改成去年的
We're married for real,
反正我们俩是真结婚
so it's not a lie, huh?
也不算骗人呀
It's not about saving face,
这面子是一回事
but about trust.
里子是另外一回事
My
反正
daughter really
我是被我的女儿
broke my heart.
伤透了心了
Mom, no...
妈你别呀
What...
你说
You're tearing up.
眼泪都快掉下来了
What can I do to make you
那你怎么才能让你
feel better?
不难受呀
Come on.
你看你
You know your mom.
你妈什么人你不了解吗
She's a party
你妈就喜欢
animal.
热闹
Think,
你想想
what's the reason
什么事能够
to throw a party?
大闹特闹一下啊
You're really married,
你俩现在不是
aren't you?
真结婚了吗
Dad.
那个爸
I see.
明白了
Mom.
妈
Alright.
这样
I'll get
我们把
the wedding plans
筹备婚礼的事情
rolling soon.
尽快提上日程
No worries.
现在就提上日程
You're thoughtful.
还是小纪懂事
So, when?
那什么时候啊
Mom.
妈
Are you happy now?
你这就高兴了
Okay.
行 行 行
We'll
那
do the wedding when we're
我们俩休完年假回来
back from vacation.
就办
That sounds good to you?
您看这日期您满意吗
Yes.
行
That's settled then.
这事就这么定了
Done.
散会
Go cook.
做饭去
Let me help you.
我帮您
My phone...
这 这 这
Check this out.
我给你看啊
It's the venue
你看这个
and
这个
decor from my
就是我们同事的儿子
co-worker's son's wedding.
结婚的那个酒店和装饰
See?
你看 你看
So pretty.
这好好看啊
The coolest thing
我跟你讲这个酒店
about this hotel?
最大的特点是什么
A bridge in the hall
就是它那个大厅里面吧
that you can walk on.
它有个桥这样过去
Imagine
到时候呢
you two,
我都想好了
the bride and groom,
就是你们新娘新郎啊
walking over it,
就从这个桥上面
right over everyone's
就从大家的脑门子顶上
heads.
就走过去了
A real-life "Magpie Bridge Meeting".
这叫做鹊桥相会
Mom.
妈
Walking over people's
从人家脑门子顶上
heads is
走过去
kinda weird,
不太好吧
and the "meeting" thing
再说这鹊桥相会
means we'll
我们俩以后
only meet once a year.
一年只见一面呀
I was talking nonsense.
我糊涂了糊涂了
Forget it.
不行 不行 不行
But anyway,
但是反正
that bridge is gorgeous.
我就觉得那个桥很美
You gotta look amazing,
到时候穿得美美的
okay?
好不好
The only
官方指定
official partner.
唯一合作伙伴
My love for you is forever,
我对你的爱没有期限
unconditional,
无需撤销
and never fades.
永不减值
Morning.
早
Tu.
小涂
Happy Marriage!
新婚快乐
Thanks.
谢谢
Thank you all.
谢谢大家
Congrats!
恭喜小涂和领导
That's amazing!
修成正果
Xiaoning,
小涂
when will you hold your wedding?
份子钱什么时候给
We've got our gift money ready.
我们可都准备好了
Xu Li.
许力
Gift money?
份子钱
Don't mention it.
份子钱就没完啦
If Fanggang was around,
小赵哥要在的话
he would cast aspersions
肯定得批评你
on you.
你挑头
Gift money...
份子钱
How about this?
这样吧
Don't worry about giving it yet.
咱们大家不着急给
I'll send the
我把二维码
payment code to the group,
直接发到群里面啊
and nobody should skip out on this.
一个都不能少
Sure.
得嘞
Now,
那咱们
once again.
再祝小涂
Happy Marriage!
新婚快乐
What's up with Mr Fu?
小付总那边是什么情况
He hit me up and said
突然跟我联系说
he's not down to
暂时不考虑
collaborate with us.
跟我们合作了
Close the door.
先把门关上
Sit.
坐
Okay, I got it.
好的我知道了
Thank you.
谢谢您啊
Mr Fu is spreading the news
小付总那边放出消息了
that he's
说要
on the hunt for a new partner.
重新找合作伙伴
Sorry, Jing.
对不起啊静姐
It's my fault.
都是因为我才没有谈成
Don't say that.
你千万别这么说啊
Neither you nor Mr Ji
你没有错
did anything wrong.
纪总也没有错
You know.
我跟你讲
If I were there,
我就是没有在现场
even pregnant,
我要是在现场
I'd give him
你别看我是个孕妇
a good slap
我高低我蹦起来
or two.
我也给他两巴掌
Alright,
行了你
calm down.
别这么激动
But it's true
但是确实
that I lost
这么大的一个客户
a big client.
在我手上给流走了呀
If we landed it,
要是谈成了的话
you'd be a department
你就能顺利转正
head by now.
部门经理了
Who knew it would fail...
谁想到临门一
I'm hormonal,
我现在孕期激素高
don't get me angry.
你不要气我好吗
My promotion is
转正经理是我的事
my business.
我的事业
Don't sacrifice
不需要你为我
your everything for it,
去拼尽全力
okay?
知道吗
I don't need you to
我更不需要你作为筹码
sell yourself for me.
去为我获得利益
If you do,
如果这个事你做了
I won't let you off easily.
我第一个知道一定骂你
And as for Mr Fu,
还有那个什么小付总啊
he's shady,
心术不正
using tricks to get deals.
威逼利诱合作方
Who wants
就这样的客户
a client like him?
谁爱要谁要
Not me anyway.
给我我都不要
Anyone in the office
咱们办公室里边
talks crap about you?
谁要是敢嚼你舌根子
You know,
我这个代经理
I'm not like Mr. Ji,
跟咱们那个纪总
I won't wait for
做事风格不一样啊
the rumors
我从来不玩那个
to die down.
清者自清那一套
Anyone who says a bad word
谁要是敢说你一句不是
about you,
我出去我就
I'll rip their mouth apart.
撕烂他们的嘴
Babe.
宝宝
Mom's talking to Xiaoning.
妈妈跟小姨说话呢
Mom's usually very gentle.
妈妈平时没这么凶的
Oh?
笑了
Happy?
高兴了
It takes a pregnant
还得我这个孕妇
leader like me
我这个领导
to cheer you up.
在这儿开导你
Figured it out?
想通啦
Ms Rao.
饶总
Your words
你刚才那番话术
really hit
反正对属下我
the spot.
是非常受用
From now on,
您放心
I'm all in for you.
我以后对您是肝脑涂地
Listen,
我跟你说啊
after this whole mess is over,
等过了眼下这一场风波
I'm giving you some time
我就给你放婚假
off for your honeymoon.
让你跟纪总出去
Go have fun with Mr. Ji.
好好开心一下
Thank you.
谢谢静姐
Damn it!
岂有此理
Fu Yijun is a total
付轶均这王八蛋
scumbag!
简直就是人渣
You did the right thing.
你打得好
If I had been present there,
我当时要在现场的话
I would have torn him apart!
我非撕了他不可
Chill out.
你也别那么大气
The
不都说了吗
Youpin thing
优品的事情
is over.
已经过去了
We gotta focus on
咱们俩现在的当务之急
finding new
是得一起找到
clients.
新的客户才行
Sit.
坐
It's a pity.
其实可惜了
You bet your next six months'
你用了未来半年的业绩
performance
做军令状
for that sweet rate.
才争取到的优惠利率
In our industry,
我们这一行一般来说
we usually negotiate for
都是业务关系
rate discounts
初步建立之后
during pricing
在定价阶段
after establishing
才能争取到利率优惠
a business relationship.
你在这个阶段
You earned that rate
为了付轶均这王八蛋
for that bastard.
向总行申请到这个点数
But he's backed out.
最终没有合作成
It's a waste.
我真的觉得很可惜
Actually, I don't
你正好说错了
think it's a waste at all.
我觉得一点都不可惜
In this long process,
这么长的时间
we all did
我们每一个人
our best,
把工作都做到位了
and we found out
同时我们也认清了
what kind of person
一件事情
he really is.
他的为人
You're right.
你说得对
He
这人啊
ain't worth our time.
就不配跟我们合作
And
而且
with our experience,
咱俩在这一行
finding new
干了这么多年
clients is a breeze.
还怕找不到客户啊
Since we work together,
咱们双剑合璧
clients will be
客户还不得
lining up.
滚滚而来
Losing Mr. Fu means
走了一个小付总
we'll get Mr. Li, Mr. Wang, Mr. Liu,
那还有小李总 小王总
and many more.
小刘总呢
Stop talking nonsense.
越说越不靠谱了
How do we move
那咱们接下来工作
forward?
怎么开展
Which client should we start with?
从哪个客户开始跑
It's a long road,
虽然任重而道远
but I've picked out a few.
但是我着重筛选了几个
Check it out.
你看看
Ms Zhu.
朱女士
I've been practicing yoga
我在咱们那儿
at your studio for two months.
练了两个月的瑜伽
I think you're doing
我觉得咱们瑜伽馆
a fantastic job.
办得特别好
I invited you here today
我今天把您约过来呢
just to tell you that
是想跟您说
if you're looking to
就如果您想
expand your studio,
拓展那个门面呀
our bank has
我们银行呢
many good
是有很多
loan options for
关于小微企业
small businesses like yours.
贷款的政策还有方案
Good.
巧了
I've been
我近期
thinking about it.
正好有这个意向
Here's the proposal.
那您先看一下方案
Hello.
您好啊
Mr Chen.
陈总
I'm Zhao Fanggang
我是
from the Dairui Ji'an Branch.
代瑞集安分行赵方刚
Nice to meet you.
幸会 幸会
You don't have to
对业务的时效性
worry about the
以及我们账户的安全
timing and security.
您都不需要考虑
Once you
其实
open a corporate
只要在我们分行
account at our bank,
办好这个对公账户
we'll assign
无论是存款
a manager to
还是贷款的业务
help with your
我们会有专门的
loans
客户经理
and deposits.
跟您进行对接的
Hello, Mr Yu.
余总
Okay.
好
Yu Hui.
余晖
Do you know anyone
你看你那边有没有需要
who needs
银行业务的朋友啊
banking
或者是
services?
客户
Refer
你
them to me, would you?
多推荐一些给我呗
Weiyi.
惟依
Let's hit the
我们晚上去
new Bar in the Sky tonight.
新开的空中酒吧
Okay?
一起吧
Drinking's boring.
吃吃喝喝有什么意思啊
Time to burn some
跟我们赛车俱乐部
rubber.
跑几圈
You haven't been out in ages.
你都好久没出来玩了
Spend your money on excitement!
钱压手里不难受啊
Nah.
不去
Gotta work.
加班
Just a receptionist gig.
现在前台还要加班啊
Your gas costs
加班费都不够你
more than that OT.
上班路上的油钱吧
Let's meet up.
见一面吧
I'll send you
时间地点
the time and place later.
我一会儿发你
How have you been?
最近过得怎么样
Same old.
老样子
And you?
你呢
We really haven't been
我们真的有一段时间
here for a while.
没有来这儿逛逛了
Yeah.
是
Those first couple years,
刚毕业那两年
we'd come back here
回来看看比赛啊
for games and food.
在附近吃点东西什么的
We
还记得
met here for the first time.
我们就是在这儿认识的
And you
当时
taught me how to do a layup.
你还教我三步上篮呢
I tried my best,
我是用心教
you didn't.
你没用心学
Took me
我好像
three tries to pass.
考了三次才过
Then,
后来呢
you and Xiaoning
你就跟筱柠
always dragged me out
晚上溜出去玩
at night.
总叫我一起
And I couldn't say no.
不去都不行
You're like our
大晚上的你要是不在
bodyguard
我们两个女孩子
at night.
多不安全
Yeah.
是
Ever since then,
其实从那个时候开始
I've had a thing for you.
我就已经喜欢你了
What's Yu Hui up to?
这余晖干吗呢
He's gonna
他今天放话
get back
要找上次
at the girl who
那个用篮球
beaned him with a ball.
砸他的女生报仇
She's in trouble.
那个女生也够惨的
Why'd she
惹谁不好
mess with him?
惹到他了
I said,
都说了
be careful after school,
下晚自习小心点啊
this is what you get.
挑衅我就这个下场
You did this, huh?
这井盖你弄的吧
Yeah, so what?
对呀怎么了
Wanna beg for mercy?
要不要求我放过你啊
Psycho.
神经病
What?
你说什么
You did it
你弄得井盖
and want me to beg you?
还让我求你放过我
You never learn.
你是不是不长教训啊
You're a loser.
你这个人真是社会败类
What?
你
You...
好你
Who...
谁啊
Don't mess with a girl.
有种就别欺负女孩
Wanna be the hero?
想当英雄是吧
Fine.
行
We'll see
比试 比试
if you're a hero or a coward.
看看你是英雄还是狗熊
You're gonna
你至于为个妞
kill me over a chick?
把我往死里揍吗
You into her?
你是不是喜欢她
Yu Hui, back off
余晖你要是还想
if you
混到毕业的话
wanna graduate.
就别招惹我
Dropping out,
中学辍学
know what that is?
你知道意味着什么吗
Your future's
你不在意
not your concern, huh?
你的前途没关系
But remember
但还记得
how your parents begged
你爸妈是怎么站在
the dean to keep you in school?
教导主任面前求他的吗
Need a refresher?
需要我告诉你吗
Threatening me
你威胁我
over this chick?
就为这个女的
Bold move.
你真有种
If next time,
你要是再敢
we'll see.
动她一下你试试